Tams-Witmark Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Tams-Witmark Collection 1701-1915 (bulk 1801-1900)
ML31.T36
Tams-Witmark Music Library
approximately 7,000 items 829 containers 164 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The Tams-Witmark Music Library was established in 1925 through the merger of the Arthur W. Tams Music Library and the rental library of M. Witmark & Sons. The Tams-Witmark Collection contains music (manuscript and printed scores) that was being performed in the United States during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The scope of the collection ranges from eighteenth-century operas of Handel and Glück to a musical by George M. Cohan. The bulk of the materials are nineteenth-century English, French, German and Italian operas and operettas, the majority in full score, with some instrumental parts. Most of the scores have been annotated with cuts and performance markings, and some feature reduced or non-standard orchestrations. The collection also contains a small amount of concert music, including secular and sacred choral works, patriotic music, symphonic scores, and incidental music.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871. Operas. Selections.; Brüll, Ignaz, 1846-1907. Operas. Selections.; Cherubini, Luigi, 1760-1842. Operas. Selections.; Cimarosa, Domenico, 1749-1801. Operas. Selections.; De Koven, Reginald, 1859-1920. Operas. Selections.; Edwards, Julian, 1855-1910. Operas. Selections.; Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Operas. Selections.; Marchetti, Filippo, 1831-1902. Operas. Selections.; Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Operas. Selections.; Millöcker, Carl, 1842-1899. Operas. Selections.; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Operas. Selections.; Reyer, Ernest, 1823-1909. Operas. Selections.; Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Operas. Selections.; Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Operas. Selections.; Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895. Operas. Selections.; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Operas. Selections.; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Operas. Selections.
Organizations
Tams-Witmark Music Library.
Subjects
Choral music.; Music--Manuscripts--18th century.; Music--Manuscripts--19th century.; Music--Manuscripts--20th century.; Musicals--Scores and parts.; Operas--Scores and parts.; Sacred music.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Acquired from the Tams-Witmark Music Library in 1969.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Other Repositories
The Tams-Witmark Music Library dispersed a large part of its older materials among five U.S. libraries: the Library of Congress, the University of Wisconsin at Madison, Princeton University, the Eastman School of Music, and Westminster Choir College. Cataloging information for Tams-Witmark materials in these other libraries can be found in box 791 of the Library of Congress Tams-Witmark Collection. The University of Wisconsin's holdings have also been catalogued on OCLC.
Access and Restrictions
The Tams-Witmark Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Agency History
The Tams-Witmark Music Library was established in 1925 by a merger between the Arthur W. Tams Music Library and the rental library of M. Witmark & Sons. The Arthur W. Tams Music Library began in 1883 as a rental library of sacred music and opera, and by the 1920's had grown to be one of the largest libraries of its kind. The Witmarks had entered the music publishing business in 1885, but started a rental library comparable to and in competition with that of Arthur Tams in 1898. The Tams library continued to acquire mostly sacred music, while the Witmark library handled popular operas and musicals, including those of Victor Herbert, Reginald DeKoven, and George M. Cohan, all of whom had publishing contracts with Witmark. After a merger between the two libraries was negotiated in 1925, the publishing firm, M. Witmark & Sons, retained separate status until it was acquired by Warner Brothers in 1928 as a part of its Music Publishers Holding Corporation. The Witmark name remained in use until 1941.
Scope and Content Note
The Tams-Witmark Library holdings reflect what was being performed in the United States during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The scope of the collection ranges from eighteenth century operas of Handel and Glück to a musical by George M. Cohan. The bulk of the materials are nineteenth century operas and operettas, the majority in full score, but there are also instrumental parts, particularly for those works from the latter half of the nineteenth century. Most of the scores have been annotated with cuts and performance markings, and some, such as Bizet's Carmen, Auber's Fra Diavolo, and Gounod's Romeo et Juliette, feature reduced or non-standard orchestrations.
Early nineteenth century opera is represented chiefly by Italian composers such as Cimarosa, Cherubini, and Rossini. In keeping with Italian practice, the vast majority of these full scores are in manuscript form. French composers are represented by comic and serious works in equal proportion, with manuscript and printed scores by Auber and Meyerbeer being the most numerous. German Romantic operas from the first half of the nineteenth century are few, but mid- to late-nineteenth century opera is well represented, with seven works by Verdi, virtually the entire operatic output of Wagner, and operas by such lesser-known composers as Ignaz Brüll, Filippo Marchetti, and Ernest Reyer.
Operettas constitute a large proportion of the collection. Jacques Offenbach is the most represented composer here, but also included are many Viennese operettas from the last decades of the 19th century, particularly those by Franz von Suppé, Johann Strauss, Jr., and Karl Millöcker. The phenomenally successful debut of H. M. S. Pinafore in Boston (1878) spawned a great demand for its performance materials. Several arrangements of this work in the collection, including one for military band, reflect the widespread use of pirated scores and parts. The collection also contains several annotated scores once used by the Boston Ideal Company (later, the Bostonians) as well as scores belonging to their rival, the McCaull Opera Comique Company.
Reginald De Koven, Julian Edwards, and Victor Herbert, all of whom gained tremendous fame during the last two decades of the nineteenth century, are well represented in this collection. The materials of De Koven and Herbert are particularly significant because they include not only finished manuscripts but also sketches and scores for numbers cut from various productions. Of special interest are the numerous scores, parts, and holograph sketches of Victor Herbert's 1912 opera Natoma. An additional strength of the collection is the large number of scores by Americans who are largely forgotten today, such as Louis Hirsch, Gustave Kerker, Thornton Cole, Frank Saddler, Willard Spenser, Henry Waller, and Woolson Morse.
Musical comedies from the early twentieth century are not well documented in the Library of Congress' portion of the Tams-Witmark collection, as most musical comedy materials from Tams-Witmark are housed at the University of Wisconsin at Madison. And, operetta composers from this period, such as Karl Hoschna, Franz Lehar, and Joseph Bayer, are marginally represented.
Concert music constitutes a small portion of the Library of Congress' Tams-Witmark Collection. Although several eighteenth and nineteenth century "masters" are represented, works by lesser-known composers are more numerous, with secular choral works such as Felix Weingartner's House of Dreams, Charles Stanford's Phaudrig Crohoore, and Joseph Rheinberger's Klärchen auf Eberstein, dominating this portion of the collection. There are also choral works of a patriotic nature, including the national anthems of Russia, Portugal, France, Great Britain, and the United States. Julian Edwards' The Redeemer, Niels Gade's Die heilige Nacht, and Adolf Jensen's Gesang der Nonnen are among the sacred choral works in the collection. Symphonic scores by Léo Delibes, Julian Edwards, and Victor Herbert appear in manuscript, some of which may be holograph. In addition, the collection includes printed full scores of incidental music by Mendelssohn, Mozart, and Schumann, as well as Sir George Henschel's music for Hamlet, and a manuscript full score of Edgar Stillman Kelley's Ben Hur. A few small scale works also appear in manuscript score. The collection also contains several manuscripts that have been reproduced; in such cases, publisher citations are added (if known).
In the following container list, all titles are recorded as they appear in the collection; translations and non-standard spellings reflect the originals. A uniform title in brackets is supplied when there is a question about the title as it appears on the item itself. Other information appearing in brackets has been derived from secondary sources. An asterisk (*) after a title signifies that the composer's name does not actually appear on the item, but was supplied, based on external bibliographical information. All printed scores are assumed to have been engraved, unless followed by the designation "(lith.)," which indicates the lithograph transfer process. Although every item in the collection shows some sign of deterioration due to age, those marked [Fragile] should be handled with special care, and may not be served, at the discretion of library staff. Individual song titles are so indicated by quotation marks.
Organization of the Tams-Witmark Collection
The Tams-Witmark Collection is organized into one series:
Music
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006568221
Container List
- Music (Box 1-829)
  - Abt, Franz, 1819-1885
    - Deutsches Voelkergebet. [Schleussinger]: Conrad Glaser, 1865, Printed full score; vocal parts.; Printed title page. (Box 1)
    - Deutsches Voelkergebet, Manuscript instrumental parts; 6 vols. (Box 1)
  - Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856
    - [Brasseur de Preston]
      - Der Brauer von Preston*, Manuscript full score (Box 2)
      - Der Brauer von Preston, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 3-4)
    - Giralde*, Manuscript full score; a few parts (Box 5)
    - Le Postillion de Lonjumeau. Paris: Schlesinger, n.d., Printed full score (Box 6)
    - Der Postillion de Lonjumeau*, Manuscript vocal parts (2 parts only); manuscript scene synopsis (Box 7)
  - Albert, Howard W.
    - The Khan of Katham (March 2, 1905), Manuscript full score (Box 8)
  - Alfredo, Aldemar
    - "Durch's hohe C." oder: Dienstmann nummer 66, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 792)
    - "Durch's hohe C." oder: Dienstmann nummer 62, Typed libretto; (3 copies). (Box 792)
    - Kampf Hähne, Typed libretto (Box 792)
  - Anschutz, Karl Friedrich Nikolaus, 1818-1870
    - Gedicht von Strachwitz, Manuscript full score (Box 8)
  - Appolloni, Giuseppe, 1822-1889
    - L' Ebreo. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 8-9)
  - Artly, Robert
    - Das Genie!, Typed libretto (Box 792)
  - Auber, D(aniel) F(rançois) E(sprit), 1782-1871
    - Le Domino noir, Printed full score (Box 761)
    - Fra Diavolo, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; Two versions. (Box 10)
    - Fra Diavolo, Manuscript full score; Acts II-III only (Box 11)
    - Fra Diavolo, Manuscript full score; Manuscript score of Italian recitatives (Box 12)
    - Fra Diavolo, Manuscript full score; Acts II-III only (Box 13)
    - Gustave ou le bal masque, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 14-15)
    - Haijdée. Paris: E. Troupenas, 1847, Printed full score (Box 16)
    - [Macon]
      - Maurer und Schlosser*, Manuscript full score (Box 16)
    - La Muette de Portici/ Die Stumme von Portici. Paris: G. Brandus et S. Dufour, 1828, Printed full score (Box 17)
    - Die Stumme von Portici. Paris: G. Brandus et S. Dufour, 1828, Printed full score; 2 vols. (Box 18)
    - Masaniello. Paris: G. Brandus et S. Dufour, 1828, Printed full score; 2 vols. (Box 19-20)
    - Muda di Portici*, Manuscript score; recitatives only (Box 20)
    - La Part du diable. Paris: E. Troupenas et Cie, 1843, Printed full score; Plate no. 1341. (Box 21)
    - La Sirene. Paris: Maison Troupenas, 1844, Printed full score; Plate no. 1550. (Box 21)
  - Audran, Edmond, 1842-1901
    - La Mascotte, Manuscript full score; miscellaneous parts (folder); [Fragile]. (Box 22)
    - La Mascotte, Manuscript parts; [Fragile]. (Box 23)
    - La Mascotte, Manuscript parts (Box 24)
    - The Mascot, Manuscript parts; 2 sets of parts in box (Box 25)
    - La Mascotte, Manuscript parts (Box 26)
    - [Noces d'Olivette]
      - Olivette, Manuscript parts (Box 27)
      - Olivette, Manuscript parts; Arranged by J.J. Braham. (Box 27)
      - Olivette, Manuscript vocal parts (Box 28)
      - Olivette, Manuscript and printed parts (Box 29)
    - [Serment d'amour]
      - The Bridal trap*, Manuscript full score; parts (Box 30)
      - Serment d'amour/Bridal trap/Love's vow. Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co., 1886, Manuscript full score; printed piano score (overture) (Box 31)
  - Bär, Lothar
    - Fidschi. Hamburg: Vertrieb Deutscher Bühnenwerke, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (from manuscript) (Box 792)
    - Fidschi, Typed libretto (Box 792)
  - Balfe, M(ichael) W(illiam), 1802-1870
    - Die Zigeunerin, Manuscript full score; Act I only; [Fragile]. (Box 35)
    - Zigeunerin*, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; Acts II-III only (Box 32)
    - The Bohemian girl, Manuscript full score (Box 33)
    - Bohemian girl, Manuscript full score (arrangement) (Box 34)
    - Die Zigeunerin, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 36-37)
    - Rose of Castile, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 38)
    - The Sleeping queen, Manuscript parts (Box 39)
  - Batchelor, W. H.
    - Sinbad, Manuscript full score (Box 39)
    - "The Bogie Man" from Sinbad. Cincinnati: John Church, Co., 1891, Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 7802-4. (Box 39)
  - Bayer, Joseph, 1852-1913
    - Der Chevalier in San Marco, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 40)
    - Der Kinder Weihnachtstraum. Hamburg: Aug. Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 41)
    - Die Puppenfee*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 41)
    - Die Puppenfee*, Manuscript full score (arrangement); [Fragile]. (Box 41)
    - Sonne und Erde (Ballet), Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies).; [Fragile]. (Box 42)
  - Bazin, François Emmanuel Joseph, 1816-1878
    - Le Voyage en Chine. Paris: Lemoine, 1865, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 42)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
    - Christus am Oelberge. Ludwig van Beethoven's Werke. Ser. 19; Kirchenwerke, no. 205. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. B 205. (Box 43)
    - Fidelio. Paris: A. Farrene, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. A.F. 72.; [Fragile]. (Box 43)
    - Fidelio (Leonore). Ludwig van Beethoven's Werke. Ser. 20; Dramatische Werke, no. B 206. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. B 206.; [Fragile]. (Box 43)
    - Fidelio. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 4682.; (2 copies).; [Fragile]. (Box 44)
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835
    - Beatrice di Tenda. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 45-47)
    - Das Castell von Ursino, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 48-49)
    - [Capuleti ed i Montecchi]
      - Romeo und Julie, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 50-51)
    - Norma, Manuscript full score; miscellaneous numbers (folder) (Box 52)
    - Norma. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 53-54)
    - Il Pirata. New York: T. Goodwin, n.d., Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; [Fragile]. (Box 55)
    - I Puritani, Manuscript parts (Box 56-57)
    - I Puritani, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; Acts I-III (Box 58-59)
    - Puritani. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Manuscript full score; Act I, book 2 only (Box 60)
    - I Puritani, Manuscript full score; Act I Finale, Act II only (Box 60)
    - La Sonnambula, Manuscript full score (condensed) (Box 61)
    - La Sonnambula, Manuscript full score; strings (original); winds (rescored) (Box 62)
    - La Sonnambula. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Printed stage band score; Plate no. 49266--XIII. (Box 62)
    - La Sonnambula, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 63)
    - La Straniera, Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 64)
    - La Straniera, Manuscript full score; Act II only (Box 65)
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869
    - La Damnation de Faust. Paris: Richault et Cie, n.d., Printed full score; English words added in manuscript.; Includes synopsis in English by Lionel S. Mapleson.; Plate no. 11605.R. (Box 66)
  - Binder, Karl, 1816-1860
    - [Tannhäuser]
      - Tannhäuser Parodie, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 67)
  - Bishop, Henry R(owley), Sir, 1786-1855
    - Guy Mannering, Manuscript full score (Box 67)
    - Guy Mannering, Manuscript parts (Box 68)
  - Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875
    - Carmen. Paris: Choudens Père et Fils, n.d., Printed full score; Entr'acte, Acts III-IV only; Plate no. A. C. 3795. (Box 69)
    - Carmen, Manuscript full score (Box 69-70)
    - Carmen, Manuscript full score; Nos. 1-2; Orchestrated by Loesch. (Box 70)
    - Carmen, Manuscript full score (condensed); 4 vols. (Box 71)
    - Carmen. Paris: Choudens Père et Fils, n.d., Printed full score; Acts I-II; Plate no. 3795. (Box 72)
    - Carmen. Paris: Choudens, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 9028.; [Fragile]. (Box 72)
  - Bochsa, Robert Nicholas Charles, 1789-1856
    - The Passions, Manuscript parts (Box 73-75)
  - Boehme, Albert
    - Das Sumpfhuhn (Der Feger mit dem Besen). Berlin: Paul Fischer, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Printed lyric sheet "Blödligkeit" laid in. (Box 792)
  - Boieldieu, François Adrien, 1775-1834
    - La Dame Blanche, Manuscript parts (Box 76)
    - Die Weise Dame*, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 77)
  - Boito, Arrigo, 1842-1918
    - Mefistofele. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1919, Printed full score; Plate no. 115310. (Box 78)
    - Mefistofele, Manuscript stage band score; 2 vols. (Box 78)
    - Mefistofele, Manuscript parts (Box 79-81)
  - Boullard, Marius, 1842-1891
    - Niniche, Manuscript parts (Box 81)
  - Bowers, Robert Hood, 1877-1941
    - Maid and mummy, Manuscript full score; Arranged by Richard Carle. (Box 82)
    - The Red rose (The Pet of Paris), Manuscript full score (Box 82)
  - Brady, S. William
    - Queen of laughter, Manuscript full score (Box 83)
  - Brandl, Johann Evangelist, 1760-1837
    - Des Loewen erwachen, Manuscript parts (Box 84)
  - Bratton, John W., 1867-1947
    - The Man from China, Manuscript full score (Box 85)
  - Briggs, B., 1859-1905
    - Dick Turpin*, Manuscript full score (Box 86)
  - Bruch, Max, 1838-1920
    - Schoen Ellen. Leipzig: C. E. W. Siegel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 5794.; (4 copies). (Box 86)
    - Das Wessobrunner Gebet, Printed full score; Plate no. F.E.C.L. 1845. (Box 86)
  - Brüll, Ignaz, 1846-1907
    - Das Goldene Kreuz. Berlin: Bote & Bock, 1870, Printed full score (lithograph); Plate no. 11149. (Box 87)
  - Buch, Soufflier
    - Samuel Peck, Printed libretto (Box 792)
  - Carr, F(rank) Osmond, 1858-1916
    - Morocco bound, Manuscript parts (Box 88)
  - Cellier, Alfred, 1844-1891
    - [Charity begins at home]
      - Charity girls/Charity begins at home, Manuscript parts (Box 89)
    - The Masque of Pandora, Manuscript parts; [Fragile]. (Box 90-91)
    - The Masque of Pandora, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 90)
    - Masque of Pandora*, Manuscript full score; 3 vols (Box 92)
    - Spectre knight, Manuscript parts (Box 93)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894
    - Merry monarch, Full score; 2 vols.; Orchestrated by J.P. Sousa; also cited: Emile Charliner, Woolson Morse. (Box 93)
  - Chassaigne, Francis, 1850?-
    - [Droit d'aînesse]
      - Falka, Manuscript parts (Box 94-95)
    - Nadjy*, Manuscript parts (Box 96)
  - Cherubini, Luigi, 1760-1842
    - [Deux journées]
      - Der Wassertraeger, Manuscript parts (Box 97-99)
      - Der Wassertreger, Manuscript full score; 3 vols.; Acts I-III; (2 copies - Act I only). (Box 100-101)
  - Cimarosa, Domenico, 1749-1801
    - Il ou Matrimonio segreto. Paris: Imabult, n.d., Printed full score; Act I only; Le Mariage secret plate no. 738. (Box 102)
  - Coedès, Auguste, 1835-1884
    - [Girouette]
      - The Weathercock, Manuscript parts (Box 103)
  - Cohan, George M(ichael), 1878-1942
    - The Royal vagabond, Manuscript full score (Box 104)
  - Cole, Thornton
    - Hawaii, Manuscript full score (Box 105)
  - Conradi, August, 1821-1873
    - Beckers Geschichte oder: Am Hochzeitstage. Berlin: Eduard Blocks, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (from manuscript) (Box 792)
    - Beckers Geschtstage, Manuscript parts (Box 792)
    - Hofsänger, Manuscript full score (Box 105)
  - Cowen, Frederic H(ymen), Sir, 1852-1935
    - The Rose maiden. London: Boosey, n.d., Manuscript and printed parts; Plate no. (H. 216) A-D. (Box 106-107)
  - Czibulka, Alphons, 1842-1894
    - [Glucksritter]
      - The May queen (Der Glucksritter*) (1889), Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 107)
    - [Jagdjunker der Kaiserin]
      - Der Jagdjunker. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 108)
    - [Pfingsten in Florenz]
      - Amorita*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 109)
  - De Giosa, Nicola, 1819-1885
    - Don Checco. Milan: Francesco Lucca, n.d., Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 110-111)
  - De Koven, Reginald, 1859-1920
    - The Algerian, Manuscript full score; Acts II-III only; Manuscript musical number listing.; Manuscript scene synopsis. (Box 111)
    - The Algerian, Manuscript full score (Box 112)
    - The Algerian, Manuscript piano-vocal score; Act I and Oh fair castle only (Box 112)
    - [Begum]
      - The Beguin, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 113)
    - Don Quixote, Manuscript full score; No. 14 and Finale 2do only (Box 114)
    - Don Quixote, Manuscript full score (Box 115)
    - The Fencing master, Manuscript full score (Box 115)
    - Foxy Quiller, Manuscript full score (Box 116)
    - The Golden butterfly, Manuscript full score; piano-vocal score Duo: Ilsa and Franz III/4 only (Box 117)
    - Can I forget. n.p.: Edward Schuberth & Co., 1900, Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 3621. (Box 117)
    - Highwayman, Manuscript full score; Fan-Tan and Chorus only (Box 118)
    - The Highwayman, Manuscript full score; 2 vols,; Acts I-III (Box 118)
    - The Little duchess, Manuscript full score (incomplete); piano-vocal score of My toast to you only (Box 762)
    - Maid Marian*, Manuscript full score (Box 119)
    - Maid Marian, Manuscript full score; piano-vocal score of Act II (opening chorus only); Manuscript musical number listing. (Box 120)
    - The Mandarin, Manuscript full score (Box 121)
    - Mandarin*, Manuscript full score (miscellaneous pages) (Box 121)
    - Nearly a hero, Manuscript full score (Box 122)
    - Hero for a day, Manuscript piano-vocal score; selections only (Box 122)
    - Rob Roy, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; Includes one printed page of piano-vocal score. (Box 123)
    - Rob Roy, Manuscript full score (Box 124)
    - Robin Hood, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; [Fragile]. (Box 125)
    - Yesterday, Manuscript full score (Box 126)
    - Yesterday, Manuscript piano-vocal score; manuscript scenario (Box 126)
    - Selections from: The Beauty spot; The Jersey lily; The Snowman; The Student king; The Yankee Mandarin, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 781)